replacements.com 2019-04-21

# Privacy Policy | Replacements, Ltd.

At Replacements, Ltd., we recognize that privacy is very important to our customers. Since we would like every customer to thoroughly enjoy their experience with us, we are dedicated to ensuring that your privacy is protected. The information below explains Replacements, Ltd.'s Privacy Policy. 

## Our Privacy Policy

When you place an order with us, or register for products or services, Replacements, Ltd. requests information from you that is required to complete your order or registration. We do not sell or rent your information to any third party. We never disclose any information to third parties for a third party's direct marketing purposes. 

## Placing an Order with Replacements, Ltd.

When you order, we request the following information: name, address, daytime phone number, and email address if you prefer to correspond with us via email. When you submit an order, this information is recorded, along with the IP (Internet Protocol) address of the computer used to place the order. In the event that a credit card is used as payment, the credit card number and expiration date are recorded. This information is utilized to authorize the purchase. The contact information you provide is used to ship the order and/or to contact the purchaser in the event there is a question about the order. If you need to update or correct this information, please contact our Internet Services Department via one of the following: 

  * Email us via our Contact Us page Regarding General Information
  * Call 1-800-737-5223 ext:2600

The information used to process your order is transferred to Replacements, Ltd. utilizing Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. [Click here](https://www.symantec.com/page.jsp?id=ssl-information-center) to confirm via VeriSign, Inc. that Replacements, Ltd. uses secure technologies to protect the transfer of your personal information. A "lock" icon in your web browser display is a typical indicator that the information you provided is being processed in a secure environment. 

## Registering for Product Information with Replacements, Ltd.

When you register for product information with us, we request the following information: name, address, and email address if you prefer to correspond with us via email. When a registration for product information is submitted, this information is recorded, along with the IP (Internet Protocol) address of the computer used to place the registration. The contact information you provide is used to send the product information updates (patterns and piece availability updates) that you request. If you need to update or correct this information, please contact our Internet Services Department via one of the following: 

  * Email us via our Contact Us page Regarding General Information
  * Call 1-800-737-5223 ext:2600

## Communications With You

We may email and/or mail you for marketing purposes and you agree to receive email and/or mail from us. For example, when you register for product information or order from us, and provide your email address, in addition to periodic updates related to your interests, you will receive email related to our products and services, specials, events, and promotions. If you decide that you do not wish to receive this communication by email, there are clearly marked opt out instructions at the bottom of each correspondence. 

We may also email you or otherwise use your information to share information with you or respond to your requests or questions. 

We may email you or otherwise use your information to send you transactional communications. For example, we may send you emails about your order, about selling to us, or about your experiences with Replacements, Ltd. 

Replacements, Ltd. reserves the right to contact users to correct account errors or to supply important information Replacements, Ltd. deems relevant, to the extent permitted by law. 

## Online Gift Cards

If you purchase a gift card online, you are asked to provide information for the recipient. We use this information to complete the order that you have placed for the recipient. In the event of a misplaced receipt or gift card, we may inform the gift card holder of the purchaser's name. 

## Gift Registries

We contract with a third party provider for online registry services for our customers who are U.S. residents; these registrants register on the provider's website and not on replacements.com. Separately, you may set up a gift registry with us via telephone or in our retail store; in those instances, the following information is requested: name, address, phone number, email address (optional), any wedding date, "ship to" address, and requested item(s) for selected pattern(s). The only information released is the "ship to" address when those purchasing for the recipient request this information. All other information remains confidential. 

When purchasing items from a registry, we request the following information: name, address, phone number, and email address if correspondence is requested via email. This information is only used to process the order and to contact the purchaser in the event there is a problem with the order and/or payment. In the event the gift recipient has misplaced a receipt or a gift card, we will inform the recipient of the purchaser's name. All other information remains confidential. 

## Disclosure to and from Third Party Companies

We do not sell or rent any information regarding our customers to any third party. We never disclose any information to third parties for a third party's direct marketing purposes. 

We may share the information we collect from and about you with companies or individuals that provide services or perform functions that enable us to serve you. To help us better serve you, we may combine information we get from you with information about you we get from third parties. These functions or services provided by other companies may include order fulfillment, package delivery, communications, postal or email delivery, customer service, data analysis, credit or payment processing, and the like. These companies or individuals may need information about you to perform their work. These companies or individuals are carefully selected and must agree to safeguard your information in strict compliance with this policy when we deem appropriate. 

If some or all of our business assets are sold or transferred, we may transfer the corresponding information regarding our customers. We also may retain a copy of that information.  
We also collect consumer information from third party providers to update or enhance our customer database or increase our understanding of our customers. For example, we may get updated addresses so that our customer address information remains current and accurate. We may also obtain information about other people from you. For example, if you order a gift to be delivered directly to a friend, you would need to give us the friend's name and address. 

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Cookies are small amounts of data that are used to "remember" specific requests and preferences that are associated with a visit to a specific website, and are also used to facilitate e-commerce transactions on millions of web sites on the Internet. If your browser is set to accept cookies, as you maneuver through various sites, your browser allocates a small amount of space on your hard drive to store these cookies. Replacements.com uses session cookies to identify items that you have expressed an interest in while visiting our site, such as items added to a shopping cart and/or our registration form. If you elect to enable the "Remember Me" feature in our web site, we will also use a cookie to save your name and address information for your next visit to our site's Pattern Registration or Order Form. If you do not elect to enable our "Remember Me" feature, we ask that you enter your name, address, and product preferences each time an order or registration is submitted online at Replacements.com. Replacements.com cookies are not used to identify, save, or retrieve personal financial information. In order to take advantage of all of Replacements.com's features, your browser should be set to accept cookies. 

In addition, we work with other companies to help serve, manage, and track our products and advertisements on the Internet. These companies may use cookies and web beacons. Web beacons are small, HTML-embedded graphic images. Web beacons assist in determining whether and how often web pages are viewed. These cookies and web beacons do not track personally identifying information. They are used to gather aggregate information to help us provide more relevant information to web visitors and to assist in making our advertising more relevant to consumers looking for our product. 

If you wish to disable cookies and web beacons, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie and web beacon management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites. 

## Advertising Networks

We may use one or more third-party online advertising networks to serve ads on our behalf on the Internet. The third-party network may collect anonymous information about your visits to our website, other websites, and your interaction with our ads. This anonymous information is collected through the use of pixel tags, cookies, or web beacons which are industry standard technologies used by most major web sites. The third-party network may use this anonymous information to provide ads about our products or services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and your choices about not having this anonymous information used by our third party service providers, please click here: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

## Protection of Replacements, Ltd. and Others

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information in special cases, such as when required by law, to comply with a regulator or investigator, judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us, to enforce or apply applicable terms and conditions and other agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of our company, our customers, or others. 

## Server Log Files

As is standard practice on the Internet, our web servers record, in an industry-standard server log file format, non-personal information regarding what resources visitors use on our web site. Additional information that is recorded includes the computer's IP address (a numerical address for a computer on the internet), the browser being used and the referring URL. We analyze this generic, non-identifiable information regarding usage trends on our site to aid in optimizing our web site usability and improving our web site user's experience with us. 

## General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), enforceable as of May 25, 2018, imposes additional requirements upon companies to strengthen the security around and enhance the protection of personal data of residents in the European Union (EU). For individuals in the EU/European Economic Area (EEA), here are details about how we use your personal data that we process as a data "controller" under the GDPR. 

### Use of Personal Data

Our use of your personal data is justified on the following legal bases: 

  * the use of your personal data is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps to enter into a contract at your request (i.e., because you have purchased something from us, sold to us, or requested information about your interests and/or our products and services);
  * the use of your personal data is necessary for us to comply with a relevant legal obligation;
  * the use of your personal data is in our legitimate interests, subject to your interests and fundamental rights, and notably our legitimate interest in using applicable data to conduct and develop our business activities; or
  * you have consented to the use.

We use the personal data we collect to: 

  * conduct and develop our business with you and with others; and
  * fulfill the purposes set forth in "Communications With You" above.

### Other Disclosures

In accordance with our legal obligations, we may also transfer your personal data, subject to a lawful request, to public authorities for law enforcement or national security purposes, and also as set forth in "Disclosure to and from Third Party Companies" above. 

Additional disclosures or information about processing of personal information related to specific websites, mobile applications, products, services, or programs may be provided to you. These may supplement and/or clarify our privacy practices in specific circumstances and provide you with additional choices as to how we may process your personal information. 

### Cookies

You may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies through our website by means of a corresponding setting of the Internet browser used, and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already-set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. If you deactivate the setting of cookies in the Internet browser used, not all functions of our website may be entirely usable. 

### Children

We do not knowingly collect, store, share or use the personal data of children under 16 years. If you are under the age of 16 years, please do not provide any personal data, even if prompted by us to do so. If you are under the age of 16 years and you have provided personal data, please ask your parent(s) or guardian(s) to notify us and we will delete all such personal data. 

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

### Retention of Your Personal Data

We keep personal data for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected. However, in some circumstances, we may retain personal data for other periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax, and accounting requirements, or if required to do so by a legal process, legal authority, or other governmental entity having authority to make the request, for so long as required. In specific circumstances, we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to a statute of limitation, so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges. 

### Your Rights

Subject to applicable law, you may have some or all of the following rights available to you in respect of your personal data: 

  * to obtain a copy of your personal data together with information about how and on what basis that personal data is processed;
  * to rectify inaccurate personal data (including the right to have incomplete personal data completed);
  * to erase your personal data (in limited circumstances, such as where it is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed);
  * to restrict processing of your personal data under certain circumstances;
  * to port your data in machine-readable format to a third party (or to you) when we justify our processing on the basis of your consent or the performance of a contract with you;
  * to withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal data (where that processing is based on your consent); and
  * to obtain, or see a copy of the appropriate safeguards under which your personal data is transferred to a third country or international organization.

In addition to the above rights, you may, subject to applicable law, have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to any processing of your personal data for which we have justified on the basis of a legitimate interest, including profiling (as opposed to your consent) or to perform a contract with you. You may, subject to applicable law, also have the right to object at any time to any processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes, including profiling for marketing purposes. 

You may, subject to applicable law, also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority for data protection. 

In relation to all of these rights, please contact us at [privacy@replacements.com](mailto:privacy@replacements.com). Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, especially if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavor to respond to your request within all applicable timeframes. 

### Contact

Replacements, Ltd.  
Attn: Data Protection Officer  
PO Box 26029  
Greensboro, NC 27420-6029  

## Your Consent

By using our website, you signify your consent to the Privacy Policy of Replacements, Ltd., and to the collection and use of your personal information as described herein. Please check this page regularly. If we post an updated Privacy Policy, you agree to the terms of the posted Privacy Policy by your continued use of our website. 

Last Updated: 05/24/2018
